Abhishek Dashora

Ethical Hacker | Security Researcher | Penetration Tester

Summary

Expertise in Application Security, Network Security, Vulnerability Assessment and Penetration Testing, Configuration Review, Network Architecture Reviews, Cyber Maturity Assessments, Cyber Security Readiness Assessments, Cyber Security Assessments.

Carried out Application and Network Penetration Testing for Web Applications and Network/Systems in various domain like Healthcare, BFSI and Retail.

Published a White Paper on 'Vulnerability Assessment and Penetration Testing'

Published a White Paper on 'Network Penetration Testing' and 'Web Application Penetration Testing'.

Expertise in Application and Network Security Concepts.

Awareness of the tools like Kali Linux, Backtrack, Burp Suite, Paros proxy, Acunetix Web Vulnerability scanner, Netsparker, Nmap, Nessus, Metasploit, Dirbuster, OWASP ZAP proxy, Soap UI, REST Client, Firebug, Xenu, SQLMAP, WinHex.

Web Application Penetration Testing, Internal and External Vulnerability Assessment, Network Penetration Testing, Computer Networking

Specialities:

Preparing Proposals on requirement for Information Security Services.

Handling end to end Technical Client Calls from project initiation to delivery.

Experience

Consultant at KPMG

February 2015 - Present (2 years 2 months)

Web Application Security, Android Application Security, Thick Client Security, Vulnerability Assessment, Penetration Testing, Device Security, Mobile Security, Telecom Security, Configuration Review, Network Architecture Reviews, Cyber Maturity Assessments, Cyber Security Readiness Assessments, Cyber Security Assessments.

Information Security Analyst at Dell

November 2014 - February 2015 (4 months)

Web Application Security, Network Security

System Engineer at Nous Infosystems

October 2012 - November 2014 (2 years 2 months)

Web Application Penetration Testing, Internal and External Penetration Testing, Vulnerability Assessment and report preparation.

Testing Web Applications and networks for OWASP top 10 and SANS top 25 vulnerabilities.

Security Testing based on OSSTMM and LPT Methodologies.

Overall co-ordination with clients and internal teams to cater to client requirements.

Hands on experience with major tools like Nmap, WinHex, Metasploit, Burp Suite, Wireshark, Nessus,

BackTrack, Acunetix, Netsparker and other vulnerability scanners.

Certifications

EC-Council Certified Security Analyst

EC-Council License ECC21868026022 March 2016 to March 2019

Certificate of Cloud Security Knowledge

Cloud Security Alliance License 554092192470 December 2016

EC-Council Certified Ethical Hacker

EC-Council License ECC98883457762 September 2014 to September 2017

CISCO Certified Network Associate

Cisco License CSCO12200625 February 2013 to February 2016

IBM Certified Academic Associate- DB2 9 Database and Application Fundamentals

IBM September 2011

IBM Certified Associate Developer- Rational Application Developer for Websphere software V6.0

IBM March 2011

Honors and Awards

Listed on AT&T Hall of Fame (Multiple Times)

AT&T

June 2014

https://bugbounty.att.com/hof.php

Listed on BlackBerry Hall of Fame

BlackBerry Limited

December 2014

http://ca.blackberry.com/enterprise/products/incident-response-team.html

Awarded by Barracuda Security Team (Multiple Times)

Barracuda Networks

October 2014

https://barracudalabs.com/research-resources/bug-bounty-program/bug-bounty-hall-of-fame-2/

Listed on Adobe Hall of Fame

Adobe Systems Incorporated

July 2014

http://helpx.adobe.com/security/acknowledgements.html

Awarded by CISCO Security Team

Cisco Systems

September 2014

http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html

Awarded by Amazon Security Team

Amazon

June 2014

Reported Critical Vulnerability to amazon.com website.

Listed on SourceForge Hall of Fame

http://sourceforge.net/

July 2014

http://sourceforge.net/p/forge/documentation/Security/#public-thanks-and-acknowledgement

Listed on Sprout Social Hall of Fame

https://bugcrowd.com/

February 2015

https://bugcrowd.com/sproutsocial/hall-of-fame

Awarded by Blackboard Security Team (Multiple Times)

https://bugcrowd.com/

November 2014

https://bugcrowd.com/

Awarded by Canvas Security Team

https://bugcrowd.com/

October 2014

https://bugcrowd.com/

Bugcrowd Leaderboard - Under Top 10 Security Researchers for the month of October 2014

https://bugcrowd.com/

November 2014

https://bugcrowd.com/leaderboard

Listed on Mahara Project Security Contributor Page

https://mahara.org

November 2014

https://wiki.mahara.org/index.php/Contributors#Security_researchers

Awarded by oDesk Security Team

https://bugcrowd.com/

October 2014

https://bugcrowd.com/odesk/hall-of-fame

Awarded by Ninefold Security Team

https://ninefold.com/

October 2014

https://bugcrowd.com/ninefold

Awarded by CoinX Security Team

https://www.coinxtrader.com/

September 2014

https://bugcrowd.com/coinxtrader

Awarded by Allianz Security Team

http://www.allianz.com.au/

September 2014

http://www.allianz.com.au/

Awarded by Blackphone Security Team

https://www.blackphone.ch/

September 2014

https://bugcrowd.com/blackphone/hall-of-fame

Listed on ServiceRocket Hall of Fame (Multiple Times)

http://www.servicerocket.com/

September 2014

https://bugcrowd.com/servicerocket/hall-of-fame

Awarded by Silent Circle Security Team

https://silentcircle.com/

September 2014

https://bugcrowd.com/silentcircle/hall-of-fame

Listed on Laer Hall of Fame

https://www.laer.in/

September 2014

https://bugcrowd.com/laer/hall-of-fame

Bugcrowd Leaderboard - Under Top 10 Security Researchers for the month of September 2014

https://bugcrowd.com/

September 2014

https://bugcrowd.com/leaderboard

Awarded by Bugcrowd Security Team (Multiple Times)

https://bugcrowd.com/

September 2014

https://bugcrowd.com/beta026/hall-of-fame

Awarded by Buttercoin Security Team (Multiple Times)

https://www.buttercoin.com/

September 2014

https://bugcrowd.com/buttercoin

Awarded by ifixit Security Team

https://www.ifixit.com/

September 2014

https://www.ifixit.com/Info/Responsible_Disclosure#Section_2014

Awarded by Kraken Security Team

https://www.kraken.com/

September 2014

https://www.kraken.com/security/bug-bounty

Listed on Abacus Hall of Fame

Abacus

August 2014

https://bugcrowd.com/abacus/hall-of-fame

Awarded by HITBTC Security Team

HITBTC

August 2014

https://hitbtc.com/

Listed on Dropcam Hall of Fame

Dropcam

July 2014

https://bugcrowd.com/dropcam/hall-of-fame

Listed on SIMPLE Hall of Fame (Multiple Times)

https://www.simple.com/

July 2014

https://bugcrowd.com/simple/hall-of-fame

Bitcasa Hall of Fame (Multiple Times)

Bitcasa

June 2014

https://support.bitcasa.com/hc/en-us/articles/202210658-How-To-Responsibly-Report-Security-Concerns Responsible Disclosure of multiple security vulnerabilities on Bitcasa.

Domain- https://bitcasa.com/

Ranked 31th among 12200 Security Researchers on BugCrowd

BugCrowd

June 2014

https://bugcrowd.com/abhishekdashora271

SNAP AWARD

Nous Infosystems, India

April 2014

Received Snap Award for Special Performance in Information Security Domain at Nous Infosystems Pvt Ltd, India

SNAP AWARD

Nous Infosystems, India

May 2013

Received an Appreciation Award for excellent performance in Information Security at Nous Infosystems Private Limited, India

Publications

Kali Linux Wireless Penetration Testing Essentials

Packt Publishing July 21, 2015

Authors: Abhishek Dashora

Technical Reviewer of the book

Web Application Security

Hakin9 Media Sp. z o.o. SK (eForensics Magazine) December 16, 2013

Authors: Abhishek Dashora

Web Application Security Guidelines.

Real time CSRF Exploitation

KALDOWN December 27, 2014

Authors: Abhishek Dashora

Projects

Web Services Penetration Testing

June 2014 to Present

Members: Abhishek Dashora

Blackbox Penetration Testing for RestFul Web Service.

Security Assessment of Google Chrome Browser Extension

March 2014 to Present

Members: Abhishek Dashora, Thyagaraju M

Security Assessment of Google Chrome Extension using manual and automated vulnerability scanning approach and look for the vulnerabilities like Cross Site Scripting, DOM XSS and CSRF.

Web Application Penetration Testing

October 2012 to January 2013

Members: Abhishek Dashora, Vandan Joshi, Thyagaraju M

Performed Manual and Automation web application penetration testing for a leading Denmark based global food and dairy company and Denmark based customer pension portal.

Network Penetration Testing

February 2012 to March 2013

Members: Abhishek Dashora, Vandan Joshi, Thyagaraju M

Performed Manual and Automation Network Penetration Testing for a leading Denmark based Healthcare Company.

Web Application Penetration Testing

April 2013 to May 2013

Members: Abhishek Dashora, Thyagaraju M

Performed Web Application Security Penetration Testing on US based leading Healthcare Organization.

Network Penetration Testing and Configuration Vulnerability Assessment

June 2013 to Present

Members: Abhishek Dashora, Thyagaraju M

Currently working on Network Penetration Testing (External Network Penetration Testing) and Configuration Vulnerability Assessment for UK based leading Healthcare Organization.

Secure Code Review

June 2013 to Present

Members: Abhishek Dashora, Thyagaraju M

We have successfully recovered hacked website of UK based client. The attacker injected the malicious code into the application thus the users were not able to load the website. We reviewed the source code of the entire application and removed the malicious code from the same. Also we conducted comprehensive web application Penetration Testing and reported the vulnerabilities to the client.

Mobile Device Management (Bring your Own Device)

August 2013 to Present

Members: Abhishek Dashora, Thyagaraju M

Implementation of BYOD methodology (Mobile Device Management, Mobile Application Management, Mobile Content Management) on small, medium and large size enterprises.

Education

Sir Padampat Singhania University Udaipur

Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech.), Computer Science and Engineering, 2008 - 2012

Grade: First Class

Activities and Societies: Secured "Hacker of the Year" Title in the University level Ethical Hacking

competition.

Courses

Independent Coursework

Certified Ethical Hacker (Training)

Cisco Certified Network Associate (Routing and Switching)

Languages

English

Hindi

Skills & Expertise

Information Security Ethical Hacker Network Security Linux Operating Systems

Unix

Computer Security

Penetration Testing

CEH

Computer Forensics

IBM Certified Rational Application Developer for

Websphere software v6.0

IBM Certified DB2 Associate

Vulnerability Assessment

Wireshark

ISO 27001

Backtrack

Nmap

Application Security

Nessus

Vulnerability Scanning

Metasploit

OWASP

Ethical Hacking

Interests

Ethical Hacking, Information Security, Penetration Testing, Vulnerability Assessment, Computer Networking

Abhishek Dashora

Ethical Hacker | Security Researcher | Penetration Tester



1 person has recommended Abhishek

"I have been working with Abhishek for approximately 2 years and I have no second thought in declaring that, Abhishek is one of the finest colleagues that I have had; the kind of dedication that he puts in is unquestionable. He is someone who has evolved more than what his experience shows on the paper. Along with his dedication and commitment, his skillset in terms of Information Security and BYOD Space, is in-par with the best in the industry. He has an excellent learning appetite which is an added plus; Abhishek is surely an asset to have with you if you are working in Information Security and BYOD Space."

— Thyagaraju M, managed Abhishek at Nous Infosystems

Contact Abhishek on LinkedIn